## WILLIAM "CHASE" WRIGHT

Chattanooga, TN · 423.902.8025

wcwright1@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/chasewright · twitter.com/thechasewright

Experienced technical data analyst with a proven record of managing people and leading cross-functional projects with partners. Strategic self-starter with strong communication skills and high emotional intelligence. Ability in articulating and communicating complex technical issues to wide tech and non-tech audiences. Experience in e-commerce, healthcare, education, immigration, and consulting.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FEBRUARY 2017 - CURRENT**

#### **INFORMATICS SPECIALIST, CIGNA**

Created a biometric dashboard that displays demographics, health and population of Cigna's clients

Provide consultative requests for Cigna's sales and client teams

Create custom ad hoc requests

**D**evelop reports and dashboards for Cigna's sales and client teams

#### **AUGUST 2015 - CURRENT**

#### MANAGING MEMBER, THE BENELLI GROUP, LLC.

Consult and plan financial goals with clients

Develop financial and strategic road maps with clients

Create KPI reports and dashboards along with ad hoc dashboards

Facilitate training on financial and data systems with client's employees

Prepare financial statements and reports for M & A interests

#### **DECEMBER 2015 – FEBRUARY 2017**

#### MANAGER, REPORTING & ANALYTICS, FILERIGHT.COM

Lead and mentor Reporting and Analytics team

Maintained key reports and dashboards

Developed a customer service staffing model based on call volume and forecasted sales

Developed process improvement guidelines

Developed a long term strategy for data integration and products

Facilitate weekly standup meetings to discuss all departmental updates

Created several performance dashboards for marketing and advertising decisions

#### **AUGUST 2014 – DECEMBER 2015**

#### **DATA ANALYST, FILERIGHT.COM**

Developed and implemented a data warehouse solution using AWS Redshift

Developed automated key metrics and trends dashboards using Mode Analytics & Jupyter Notebooks

Managed a team of data scientists and an accountant

Created automated key metric reports for the Financial, Marketing, Customer Service and C - Level groups

Developed a payment gateway alerting system

Created and maintained a Github repo that contains all version controlled queries, code, etc

**D**eveloped ad hoc analysis

**D**eveloped Redshift documentation and quick start guide for incoming Analysts who join the team **D**eveloped python email services to deliver time series reports to stakeholders

APRIL 2011 – JULY 2014

ANALYST, CGI (FORMERLY CTS, INC.)

Maintained fiscal systems for monitoring and forecasting project activities for our internal team Built and maintained automated Excel spreadsheets and macros for our internal team Handled tasks like reviewing, maintaining and highlighting the changes in project plans Maintained resource allocation and utilization

Built a front end reporting solution for a major insurance company
Lead a team of analysts and created over 70 reports for a major insurance company
Created a POC for a major nuclear company using Microsoft SharePoint, Yammer, and Office 365

# DECEMBER 2008 – MARCH 2011 ACCOUNTANT, UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA AT BIRMINGHAM

Audited Title IV federal loans

Managed and reconciled over \$100m dollars in student deposits annually

Analyzed and reconciled monthly reports

Managed cashiering staff in student accounting

Worked with TouchNet, Banner, and Oracle Software

#### **EDUCATION**

**MAY 2012** 

MASTERS OF ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA AT BIRMINGHAM

MAJOR: INFORMATION ENGINEERING

GPA: 4.0

**DECEMBER 2008** 

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINSTRATION, UNIVERSITY OF MONTEVALLO

MAJOR: FINANCE

GPA: 3.0

#### **SKILLS**

- LEADERSHIP
- TIME MANAGEMENT
- ACCOUNTABILITY
- BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE
- ACCOUNTING
- PROJECT PLANNING
- FINANCIAL ANALYSIS
- RESOURCE MANAGEMENT
- FORECASTING
- FOCUS

- PYTHON
- SQL
- R
- TABLEAU
- AWS
- DATA WAREHOUSING
- MICROSOFT DATA STACK
- MICROSOFT EXCEL
- DATA ANALYSIS
- GIT

- PERSISTANCE
- DEPENDABILITY

- HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT
- DATABASE MANAGEMENT

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER
- MICROSOFT CERTIFED SOLUTIONS ASSOCIATE
- MICROSOFT CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL

#### **ACTIVITIES**

#### **INDEPENDENT CONSULTANT:**

Worked with Everlee Farm founder's to kick start their marketing and website efforts before the launch of their venue. <a href="www.everleefarm.com">www.everleefarm.com</a>

#### SPEAKER:

Spoke at different schools around Chattanooga, TN promoting STEM education.